Guide to the Stanford Polo Association Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Polo Association records
1947-1953
SC0245
Stanford Polo Association.
1.5 Linear feet
This collection consists of correspondence, minutes, game records, clippings, photographs, and a scrapbook. The scrapbook, assembled by Robert M. Lawson (president of the association), documents the association's first year (1947-48) and includes clippings, photographs, charter, and narrative accounts of membership, training, playing, finances, and each quarter's season.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Mrs. Allen I. Ross, 1981.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The Stanford Polo Association, a student group, was organized in the spring of 1947; prior to that, the polo team had been sponsored by ROTC. Allen Ross, Director of the Stanford Riding School, was its first coach.
Description of the Collection
This collection consists of correspondence, minutes, game records, clippings, photographs, and a scrapbook. The scrapbook, assembled by Robert M. Lawson (president of the association), documents the association's first year (1947-48) and includes clippings, photographs, charter, and narrative accounts of membership, training, playing, finances, and each quarter's season.
Access Terms
Elwing, Arthur C.; Lawson, Robert Mallory.; Ross, Allen I.; Stanford Polo Association.; Thompson, Dan.; Photoprints.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Correspondence, 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Horse shows (programs, schedules, announcements), 1948-52 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Record of games, 1949-50 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes and finances, 1952-53 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Game records: goals and fouls, 1953 and undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Rules of play (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, 1947-51 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, 1949-52 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, action shots, 1953 and undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, action shots, Santa Barbara, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, groups, 1950 and undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, color snapshots (with some negatives), 1950-52 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Photographs, mixed (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Photograph removed from scrapbook (Todd Helser) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Photographs removed from scrapbook (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Text removed from scrapbook (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Clippings removed from scrapbook (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Scrapbook, 1947-48 (Box 2)